b-europe.com 2016-04-03

# Privacy policy of the SNCB Europe website, mobile apps and SNCB Europe sales outlets

## 1\. SCOPE 

SNCB Europe, a division of the National Company of Belgian Railways (SNCB), cares about your privacy, and in this respect always acts in accordance with the provisions of the Belgian Privacy Law _(Law of 8 December 1992 on the protection of privacy in relation to the processing of personal data)_. Read this Privacy Policy to find out more about the way personal data are collected and processed on this website (hereafter referred to as "Website"), in SNCB Europe apps (mobile applications to be downloaded on smartphones and smart tablets via app stores, hereinafter referred to as "Apps"), at the SNCB Europe Contact Center or at the SNCB ticket offices at stations selling international rail tickets and connected products marketed by SNCB Europe.

**By  buying international rail tickets and connected products through these SNCB Europe sales outlets, by using the SNCB Europe Website or Apps and by communicating personal data, you formally agree with the conditions mentioned below under which SNCB Europe collects, processes and transfers and/or (depending on the case) you guarantee that these conditions have been communicated to and accepted by the individuals concerned to whom the personal data relates**.

## 2\. SECURITY 

SNCB Europe undertakes to take all suitable technical and organizational measures to protect your personal data against destruction, loss, unintentional modification, damage or disclosure.

In order to guarantee this security, SNCB Europe makes, among other things, periodical back-ups.

## 3. PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA 

3.1. Collection, processing and purposes of the personal data on the Website and the Apps

For each use of the Website or when using the Apps, different personal data and log files about you are collected, i.e. your IP address, the website from which you are redirected to the Website, the date and duration of your use of the Website, your browser, your operating system, your online surfing behaviour and history in the Website and, more particularly, the pages you visit on the Website.

These data are only used for statistical purposes and to analyze and optimize the functioning and the use of the Website and the Apps. To this end, SNCB Europe uses the services of third parties to which these data are communicated for these purposes. 

From the moment your visit is not limited to general information gathering and, more specifically, when, on or through the Website and/or the Apps, you 

(i) You use the booking function to buy a ticket or to order another product or service,

(ii) register for a MyTrain account,

(iii) contact SNCB Europe,

(iv) participate in a contest, 

(v) agree to receive the SNCB Europe newsletter or information about SNCB Europe products and services, or

(vi) agree to activate certain services when downloading the Apps, such as directions to the nearest train station on the basis of your location and the use of your contacts and file/image directories,

additional data is requested and/or collected, including your gender, name, email address, password, possible purchase order history and, if applicable, telephone number, address, language, and travel preferences and arrangements. 

Such data are used respectively 

(i) for the creation of a purchase file in order to be able to confirm your booking or order, to provide you, where appropriate, with further information in this respect, to provide you and follow the corresponding products or services, to guarantee the after-sales service and continually improve the service offered to you and adapt this service to your requirements, in particular by offering you personalised services likely to be of interest to you, based on customer profiles created. Likewise, an email offering assistance will be sent to you if your purchase is interrupted for whatever reason, on the condition that you have sent us your details using the booking tool; 

(ii) to let you enjoy all the benefits of your MyTrain account, including a simplified booking and ordering procedure and access to your purchase order history, to the online after-sales service for active bookings and to your own profile data for the management thereof, as well as for purposes of customized marketing via emails and adaptation of the Website according to your preferences and history order; 

(iii) to deal with your question, request or communication and to answer if applicable; 

(iv) to let you participate in the contest and to inform you about the progress and completion thereof, as well as, following your consent, for purposes of customized marketing via email and the newsletter;

(v) to provide you with the newsletters and customized marketing via emails with your agreement;

(vi) to enable you to take part in satisfaction surveys relating to the products and services offered by SNCB Europe;

(vii) to enable you to enjoy additional services in the Apps, such as directions to the nearest train station, the function of priority direct calling to our services for help with booking your journeys and saving your digital transport tickets in the directories of your smart phone or smart tablet;

and, to these ends, can be transferred to third parties or subcontractors as explained under point 3.4. below. 

In addition, in order to prevent potential fraud when tickets are purchased, SNCB Europe will check the accuracy of all the details you have provided at the time of each transaction. 

3.2. Collection, processing, and uses of personal data at the SNCB Europe Contact Center

When you call the SNCB Europe Contact Center to make a purchase or request after-sales support, your personal data will be requested and/or collected, including your gender, name, e-mail address and, if relevant, the financial details needed for a payment or refund, your telephone number, address, language, and travel preferences and arrangements. 

These data will be used 

(i) to set up a buyer record so that your booking or order can be confirmed, and to provide you with any additional information, supply and track the relevant products and services, guarantee after-sales service and continually improve the service offered to you and adapt this service to your requirements, in particular by offering you personalised services likely to be of interest to you, based on customer profiles created; 

(ii) to complete and amend a buyer record in the event of changes or cancellations to a previously booked journey, so that any after-sales support requested can be provided and any refund paid; 

(iii) to send you newsletters and customised e-marketing, subject to your consent;

(iv) to enable you to take part in satisfaction surveys relating to the products and services offered by SNCB Europe.

For these purposes, they may be passed on to third parties or subcontractors, as explained in 3.4 below.

In addition, in order to prevent potential fraud when tickets are purchased, SNCB Europe will check the accuracy of all the details you have provided at the time of each transaction.

3.3. Collection, processing, and uses of personal details at SNCB station counters selling international rail tickets and connected products marketed by SNCB Europe

When buying specific products which are in your name and are non-transferable by virtue of their special conditions (such as certain season tickets or unlimited travel passes), requesting after-sales support involving refunds, or picking up rail tickets previously paid for by a third party, your personal data will be requested and/or collected, including, if and as required, name, date of birth, address, language, financial data if required for a refund, and, if necessary, the relevant details from your identity card or passport (see iii below) 

These data will be used 

(i) to create the travel document (pass or season ticket) in your name, in compliance with its special conditions of use; 

(ii) to complete and amend a purchase file in the event of change or cancellation of a journey previously booked, so that the after-sales support requested can be provided and any refund paid, or 

(iii) to hand over international rail tickets and any other products marketed by SNCB Europe which are booked and paid for remotely (by phone, online, or at a travel agency recognised by SNCB Europe), when the person picking up the rail ticket or other product is unable to provide the confidential code given on purchase or the credit card used to pay for the rail ticket or other product, solely for purposes of fraud prevention. 

They may therefore be passed on to third parties or subcontractors, as explained below 

3.4. Transfer to third parties or to subcontractors 

SNCB may also transfer certain personal data to third parties, among other things, for the following purposes: 

  * To the partners of SNCB Europe as indicated in the Website, in brochures or in any other material published by SNCB Europe (for example, hotels, rental car companies, carriers) for the management and performance of the travel contract, the contract of carriage and/or another service or product of SNCB Europe; 
  * To travel agencies recognized by SNCB Europe for the management and performance of the travel contract, the contract of carriage and/or another service or product of SNCB Europe; 
  * To the competent authorities in case of threatening or pending legal proceedings. 

These third parties act as a "data controller" in relation to the performance of this and other processing of personal data. For more information regarding this processing, SNCB Europe also refers to the applicable privacy policy of these third parties. 

SNCB may also transfer personal data to other natural or legal persons acting as subcontractors on behalf of SNCB. In this case, they only have access to the data which are strictly necessary to the fulfilment of their task. 

3.5. International transfer 

By using the Application or disclosing your personal details to SNCB Europe, you expressly acknowledge and agree that, in the framework of the mentioned processing of personal data, data can be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area, not affording a similar level of protection for personal data.

## 4\. COOKIES 

The Website uses so-called "cookies", i.e. small files of information which are stored, temporarily or permanently, on your computer or device by the server of a website through the browser and that simplify, complement and customize the use of the Website. 

In your browser, you can disable the storage of cookies or remove registered cookies but this may lead to a reduced functionality, slowdown or inability to use certain parts of the Website

For more information on cookies and how you can remove them according to the type of the browser used, SNCB Europe refers to the following web site: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

SNCB Europe uses the following cookies: 

**1\. Strictly necessary cookies**  are cookies which allow visitors to look at the Website, to use the functions on the Website (such as your shopping basket during an order) and to gain access to the secure and registered parts. If the use of these cookies is disabled, certain parts of the Website may not be able to be used correctly. 

**2\. Performance cookies**  are cookies designed to collect information on how visitors use the Website, such as information about the pages visited or the number of error messages that have appeared, in order to analyze and optimize the use of the Website. 

**3\. Functional cookies and saving preferences** are cookies which allow SNCB Europe to recall the choices (such as the user's name, recent bookings, choice of language and country, font and size of script, etc.), as well as visitor preferences (such as pages visited, etc.), in order to facilitate use of the Website and be able to offer visitors the most relevant and personalised information and advertising. 

**4.  Advertising cookies** are cookies placed on the Website by third parties such as affiliated companies and advertisers who are part of the advertising network of the Website and are the only type of cookies that are used for marketing purposes, more specifically in order to present relevant and customized advertisements, to determine and limit the number of times each advertisement is presented, to measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign, and to remember the visit and to share the collected data with third parties such as advertisers.

SNCB Europe uses the following remarketing cookies: 

  * **Google Remarketing cookies** , the aim of which is to show personalised advertising (based on your previous visits to the Website) via Google's Display Advertising network, and from which you may [unsubscribe via this ink](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCjEMnZyAtp0RxsCMK20YroREpP1Ur7nATWMJqdzvR0nANYN5QXj0OmdQsSAdP8DUqy9BtErR0aqkrYtps1nDb1wgAk2lQoUN4wltVaRKoOvGg7s_qDKQzYeWRbz78cpWgVj1Ao02xfIkSfM7BOjIbptuXot-6wGjWNQS_LOlrPZa1ElrYuz4vEsOgxTUJEaACfr7JZz%20). 
  * **MyThings retargeting cookies** , the aim of which is to show personalised advertising (based on your previous visits to the Website) via the MyThings advertiser network, and from which you may unsubscribe via this page: <http://ww2.mythings.com/optout.htm>
  * **Facebook remarketing cookies** , the aim of which is to show personalised adverts (based on your previous visits to the Website) on the social networking website, Facebook. You can unsubscribe from any kind of advertising cookie – including Facebook cookies – via the link <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>. 

The issue and use of cookies by third parties is subject to the privacy policies of said companies. For more information on this use, SNCB Europe is therefore also sending the applicable privacy policies of these third parties.

Social media networks

The SNCB Europe website is likely to include third-party applications allowing you to share website content with others or to inform others of your visit or opinion on website or app content. This is particularly the case with 'Share' and 'Like' buttons on social media networks such as 'Facebook', 'Twitter', 'LinkedIn', etc. The social media network offering such a button may, where appropriate, place cookies on your browser and use this button to identify you. In the same way, a social media network may place cookies on your browser when visiting the SNCB Europe social media web page. SNCB Europe refers you to the privacy policy of these social media networks so that you are aware of the use, in particular with regard to advertising, of browsing data which may, where appropriate, be collected in this regard.

## 5. RIGHT OF ACCESS, ADAPTATION AND RECTIFICATION 

As provided for by the Privacy Law, you have a right, free of charge, of objecting to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes, and a right of access, adaption and rectification of your personal data at any time in writing to the SNCB Europe's service responsible for the processing, at the address indicated below, with a proof of your identity. 

If you have a MyTrain account, you have the option to manage and modify your profile data by yourself and to choose to stop receiving emails or text messages from SNCB Europe. 

## 6\. CONTACT INFORMATION 

SNCB Europe is a division of the National Company of Belgian Railways (SNCB), a limited company under public law, Rue de France 56, 1060 Brussels, Belgium (VAT / Brussels company number: BE 0203.430.576).

SNCB is responsible for the processing of these personal data and ensures the privacy and security of these data. 

You can contact SNCB (division SNCB Europe) at the following address: **Customer Care  Europe**, **10-14 B-MS.035** ,  **Avenue de la Porte de Hal 40** , **1060 Brussels** (Belgium) or by email via the [Customer Care Europe contact form](http://www.b-europe.com/Travel/Practical/Contact%20us/Client%20Service). 

SNCB Europe reserves its right to amend at any time this Privacy Policy.
